rengineeringjobs.com 2018-12-03

# Privacy policy: Engineering and Construction Jobs

Privacy policy

LEGAL PRIVACY POLICY for (The Website)  **www.rengineeringjobs.com**

We at R Job Network Ltd trading as www.rengineeringjobs.com respect the privacy of our visitors and are committed to preserving your online safety by preserving your privacy at any time you visit or communicate or store your personal details with our site. 

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority in your local country or region if you believe that your data has been processed in a way you did not consent to or further issue relating to your data and how we handle it.

REngineeringjobs.com is a trading brand of R Job Network Ltd. All R Job Network brands are a part of a global online job board network and data company that operates online job portals which, using purpose-built software, provides our community with relevant job opportunities and introductions to companies seeking to hire.

R Job Network is a company built with the aim of providing users with a portal/forum where relevant work and career opportunities can be viewed and applied for.

During the course of our normal operations is it required that the candidates input their information to our site. It is further a core function of our site that the information gathered from candidates in made available to clients seeking connections with jobseekers.

By applying to a job via this site you are authorising for your details to be sent to the company advertising such vacancy, including and not limited to direct employers, recruitment and employment agents, recruitment process outsourcing companies and advertising agencies.

Please do not submit personal information to R Job Network if you do not wish us to collect and use to create your profile, we may use any data we hold on you to tailor our marketing and communications preferences under legitimate interests unless specifically opted out.

Regarding data protection, we take data protection very seriously and understand the importance of protecting your privacy and Personal Information. “Personal Information” is information that identifies you as an individual such as your name, date of birth, email address, IP address and CV.  

Please do not submit personal information to R Job Network if you do not wish us to collect and use to create your profile. Also, please bear in mind, a large amount of your personal information is contained in your Resume/CV, cover letter, or application to a job. Please do not include any details in your CV, and allow for that CV to be searched within the client database that you do not wish to be shared with potential employers or their agents.

Our Terms of Use and Privacy Policy offers you a thorough explanation regarding your personal data provided to us or any data we may collect from you.

This Privacy Policy is updated from time to time, usually as a result of new legislation or new ”best practice” methods being discovered, therefore, Our Privacy Policy should be reviewed occasionally to ensure you are happy that the way we are collecting and using your Personal Information, and that it remains in accordance with our current Privacy Policy.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998, Mr Craig Bines is our data controller and can be contacted via [info@rjobnetwork.com](mailto:info@rjobnetwork.com)

 **1\. Collected Information**  
Personal data is collected and processed during the normal operations of our website. The following are ways we may collect your data, together with examples of information that is often included:

1.1 Technical data regarding your visit(s) to our website and any affiliated resources used are collected. The following is included but not limited to: location data, weblogs, traffic data, and any other communication information.

 1.2 General identification and contact information can include: your IP Address, name, address, telephone details, positions held, qualifications, gender, status, family status, date of birth, place of birth, interests, hobbies, and skills developed. Again, this list should not be viewed as exhaustive as the contents of any documents uploaded by the candidate would be entirely beyond our control.

1.3 Any information submitted by candidates, such as registration forms, CV uploads completed on our site can be added to the candidate profile via the selected methods

 1.4 Any physical attributes including photos, blogs, or references

1.5 If for any reason you communicate with our personnel or site we may collect information as a matter of record, this can also include unsubscribe requests, removal of account and subject access requests. We may continue to hold such information even after other information we hold may have been removed but only for the purpose of record keeping. 

 1.6 Inputted information can and has included:  Sensitive information including religious beliefs, political memberships, ethnic origin, criminal record, and driving license and passport information. 

 1.7 Marketing preferences, including: contests, prize draws, customer satisfaction surveys, salary details, and email matching partners and courses

 1.8 Statistical information, including: site visits, users and demographic details, to provide reporting details and other lawful purposes. We may provide this information to customers, advertisers, suppliers, third party aggregators, and other reputable third parties. At all times where we provide such information then we will provide this in an anonymous format and not include any personal information unless otherwise stated.

 1.9 Public available information relating to the employment history, educational, professional history, educational, skills and experience data, blogging or any professional association relating to job seeking.

 **2\. Cookie Usage**  
There are instances where we may use cookies to gather information regarding our services in a mathematical collection for our website and our advertisers.

Any information collected will not have any identifying data. It is statistical data about our visitors and how they have used our site. No personal details will be shared that could identify you.

We may assemble information about your common internet use with a cookie file. When used, the cookies are downloaded to your computer automatically. The cookie is stored on the hard drive, with transferred information. The data sought by the cookie helps us improve our website and any service offered to you.

Your browser has the ability to decline cookies. This is done by setting your browser options to decline all cookies.

Note: if you do decline the download of cookies, some aspects of our site may not work or allow you access.

Our advertisers may download cookies to which we have no control. If used, these cookies are downloaded by clicking on an advertisement found on our website.

 **3\. Our Use of Your Information**  
Information stored or collected regarding you helps us improve our practices and offer new services you need. The following list contains how we might use the collected data which may then be disseminated to our websites across the R Job Network’ estate:

3.1 Any request you make of our site or personnel allows us to use information you provided us with, relating to the products or services we have. We may also send information on products or services you may be interested in, as long as consent has been received.  

 3.2  We may make the information available to any member for the R Job Network group of companies along with and not limited to : Recruitment Consultancies, Corporate Clients, Fixed Free Recruiters, Media Agencies, Third Party Suppliers, Partners, Email Providers and other intermediaries and agents relating to employment opportunities and forfilling our agreement with you.

3.3 Contract Commitments: To meet any Commitment we make to you.

3.4 Changes or improvements made to the site can warrant use of your information, with regard to notification of such changes.

3.5 An existing customer may be contacted regarding products and services related to any item of previous interest you made on our site.

3.6 We may use data or allow third parties to use information that is not related to goods or services you may be interested in. We or third parties contact you only if consent has been provided by you at any time, based on information we collected under legitimate consent 

3.7 Any new customer can only be contacted by us or a third parties if consent has been offered via our site. We only send communications from this site that you have consented to.

3.8 Anyone who does not wish to give consent for our site or third-party use, can decline. Once we receive your “withhold for consent”  notice by email or you use such mechanical in your candidate dashboard we will remove your details from any mailings or third party communications.

3.9 None of the information collected about you other than what you make public will offer identifiable characteristics. Information shared to a third party is statistical only. We will not reveal who you are, only mathematical and statistical information about our visitors unless opted in.

 3.10 Typically, we will communicate with you via email, mobile, push notifications and/or SMS via a range of topics but primarily with:  
-   job matches  
-   policy changes with R Job network,  
-   administrative information including policy changes  
-   research, surveys and competitions  
-   training and courses  
-   job seeking related improvements  
-   blogs, advice on recruiting and job seeking trends  
-   salary information  
-   data trends and reports  
-   affiliated job opportunities 

**4\. Managing your Personal Information**

When you create any account with www.rengineeringjobs.com , it is protected by your password and may only be accessed by you. You can manage the content and information in your account by logging into your Job seeker account.

 Your Resume/CV can be viewed by R Job Network customers should you have specified consent to be viewed in the database. Also, your email job agents notifications can be managed accordingly via the job seeker dashboard and opt out links provided on all email communications

 You can change, deactivate and delete your account at any time.

 If you wish to delete your account permanently then please send an email to our Data Protection Officer – including your full name and current email address.

   **5\. Personal Data Storage**  
5.1 Locations outside the European Economic Area (EEA) may be used for transferring data we collect about you. These data sites are for storing or processing of your information. The information we share outside the European Economic Area may be shared with staff based on the process and storage of said data. It may include such processes as processing a payment or offering support for your service or product needs. The staff processing or storing information may work for our suppliers outside the European Economic Area. By submitting your data to use you have agreed to this transfer and storage of data. We take all reasonable action to ensure the safety of your personal data in agreement with this Privacy Policy. Due to the global nature of our business, and technologies required, your Personal Information may be transferred to third party service providers outside the EEA where there may be a lower legal level of data protection. In all circumstances we will only enter legal contracts in accordance with this privacy policy and the European levels of data protection.

5.2 Information we are provided with will be stored on secure servers. Transaction data is encrypted for your safety.

5.3 You should understand data transferred via online transmission can never be completely secure. We cannot guarantee full protection and security of data, only that we take all reasonable action to protect information sent to us electronically. Transmission of any data by you is at your own risk. Where applicable you may be given access to sections of our site that require a password. You are responsible for the passwords safety and its confidentiality.

 **6\. Information Disclosure**  
At times we may disclose personal information to persons in our group. This can include subsidiaries, holding companies, or any other subsidiaries involved in our business, if applicable.

6.1 Third Party disclosure may occur for the following reasons:

\- Selling any or all of our business to a third party may result in sharing your information.

\- At any time when we are legally required to we may disclose information about you and your visits to our sites.

\- To prevent fraud and help in fraud protection in order to reduce credit risk, we may disclose information.

 **7\. Third Party Links**  
Third party links may be discovered on our site. These third-party links have their own privacy policy, which you agree to when you click on the link. We are not responsible, nor do we accept responsibility, for third party links. Our liability covers us only on our site, and thus we do not accept liability for third-party links as we have no control over them.

 **8\. Information Accessibility**  
We cannot withhold access to the data we collect about you, as per The Data Protection Act 1998. This act provides you with access to any information we may hold on you and you are granted the following rights:

\- the right to ask what personal data we hold about you at any time and if you wish to have access will be subjected to a fee by law.

\- the right to update any information and correct any data we hold

\- the right to opt out of any marketing communications that we may send you a reply within 30 days of any request

We can refuse a request if we believe the request is unfounded for any reason. The requestor will receive communication stating the reason(s) why within 30 days.

Please use the contact details below to formulate your data access request.

**8\. Contacting Us**  
Please feel free to contact us with queries, requests, or comments you may have about our Privacy Policy. We welcome any communication via the email address supplied here: info@rjobnetwork.com

**9\. Changes to the Policy**

We regularly review the Privacy Policy and reserve the right to make changes at any time to take into account changes in legal, political, and business requirements. Updates will be placed on our sites and can be viewed as “Last Updated”.

Last Updated 14/06/2018
